# RYAN LANDMAN

For the past 12 years I've worked both in-house and within an agency environment developing responsive websites and web applications for all types of clients. My focus is in front-end development (though I do have expericence with back-end development, primarily PHP and Wordpress). I've found that my background in graphic design has helped me collaborate effectively with designers to bridge the gap between creative and development.



P: 610-585-4590

E: ryan.landman@gmail.com

W: landman.dev

## EXPERIENCE

September 2020 – Present

P'UNK ΔVENUE

### **Senior Developer**

Responsible for full-stack development of client web sites and applications (focused on front end).

April 2019 - May 2020

1600VER90

#### Senior Front End Developer / Interim Tech Lead

In addition to my previous responsibilities at 160over90, I was also tasked with leading client conversations around technology/recommending solutions, mentoring Junior Developers, and improving the efficiency of the development process. During this time I worked closely with Producers to implement a process for accurately scoping development effort while eliminating scope creep throughout the UX/Design phases. I also developed a framework for rapidly building landing pages using a collection of components common to all historical projects.

April 2018 - April 2019

1600VER90

#### **Front End Developer**

Developed client websites for both higher education and consumer clients with an emphasis on web accessibility best practices and WCAG 2.1 compliance. I worked closely with the Design team to translate atomic design systems into scalable and mainatainable component libraries, leveraging Vue.js for all interactivity. Clients included: Blue Origin, The Philadelphia Zoo, LSU, Jefferson University, University of Pennsylvania, and Rowan University.

June 2017 - April 2018

QUATTRO

#### **Senior Web Developer**

Responsible for front and back-end development of all internal and client web sites (Wordpress and static), as well as landing pages and emails with Hubspot integration. I also managed and mentored a Junior Developer/QA Analyst.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF THE ARTS

**BFA Graphic Design, 2008** 

Philadelphia, PA

SKILLS

 HTML
 CSS
 JavaScript
 Vue.js
 PHP
 Twig
 Web Accessibility

 Wordpress
 Photoshop
 Illustrator
 Sketch
 Project Management